Someone has come along.
Logan is a action, drama, science fiction film directed by James Mangold.
In the near future, a weary Logan cares for an ailing
Professor X in a hideout on the Mexican border.
But Logan's attempts to hide from the world and his legacy are upended
when a young mutant arrives, pursued by dark forces.
Logan / X-24, played by Hugh Jackman.
Laura, played by Dafne Keen.
Charles, played by Patrick Stewart.
Gabriela, played by Elizabeth Rodriguez.
Pierce, played by Boyd Holbrook.
Caliban, played by Stephen Merchant.
Logan is a 2017 American superhero film starring
Hugh Jackman as the titular character.
Based on the Marvel Comics character Wolverine, the film was directed by James Mangold, who
co-wrote the screenplay with Michael Green and Scott Frank from a story by Mangold.
It is the tenth in the X-Men film series and the third Wolverine solo film
following X-Men Origins: Wolverine (2009) and The Wolverine (2013).
The film takes inspiration from  the "Old Man Logan" comics storyline by Mark Millar and Steve McNiven, follows an aged Wolverine and an
extremely ill Charles Xavier who must defend a young mutant named Laura from the Reavers led by Donald Pierce and Zander Rice.
In addition to Jackman, the film also stars Patrick Stewart, Richard E.
Grant, Boyd Holbrook, Stephen Merchant, and introduces
Dafne Keen in her film debut as Laura.
Discussion for the film began following the release of The Wolverine in 2013, with Mangold in
negotiations to write the treatment for the film and Lauren Shuler Donner returning to produce.
After updates followed that December to May 2016, principal photography began that May,
and ended that August, mainly in Louisiana, New Mexico, and Mississippi.
The film was designed to look like it takes place in the near future, with slight updates to technology and
the social environment, with heavy influences from the Western genre, akin to a Neo-Western.
Logan premiered at the 67th Berlin International Film Festival on February 17,
2017, and was theatrically released in the United States on March 3.
It was praised by critics for its action scenes, emotional depth, performances, and
Mangold's direction, becoming the best-reviewed film in the X-Men franchise.
The National Board of Review named Logan one of the top-ten films of 2017, and the film was also nominated for Best Adapted
Screenplay at the 90th Academy Awards, becoming the first live-action superhero film to be nominated for screenwriting.
Grossing $619.2 million worldwide, it became the
third-highest-grossing R-rated film at its release.
Jackman and Keen reprised their roles in the film Deadpool & Wolverine (2024).
The film explores themes of future, experiment,
immortality, self-destruction, cyborg.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and emotional.